<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chris George (Posts about ecolocide)</title><link>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/categories/ecolocide.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:technatica@gmail.com"&gt;Chris George&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 20:13:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Summer Again</title><link>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/summer/</link><dc:creator>Chris George</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I keep waiting for the smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past three years we have had thick wildfire smoke as a feature of our summers. This year it is wind and rain and cooler temperatures. The cherries sucked and the birds got ALL of them. I have been watching two robins strip our pin cherries of their bounty. They work hard. At least all of the apple trees had good pollination and seem to be working on a decent crop of apples. So much so that thinning is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the up side the black currants are lovely; fat, juicy, and if not sweet, at least not mind puckeringly tart like they are most years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tomatoes and the basil are struggling a bit. Next year we'll stick some peas in the ground to give us more weather options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cannabis plants, on the other hand, are lovely. This is the first season that we can grow it here legally in Canada. The ones in pots are booming right along and the one in the ground is finally starting to stretch a bit as it digs its roots in. Only a couple of months to wait and we'll see what outdoor grown B.C. bud is like here this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am still waiting for the smoke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>ecolocide</category><category>weather</category><guid>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/summer/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 01:47:12 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>