<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chris George (Posts about internet)</title><link>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/categories/internet.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:technatica@gmail.com"&gt;Chris George&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:55:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Ugh! Speed Matters.</title><link>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/ugh-speed-matters/</link><dc:creator>Chris George</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember me commenting on how many things don't work on the internet without high-speed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wasn't counting on was something as simple as file transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was puttering around on my computer and decided to install a text editor I had read about. One of the prerequisites was QScintilla2. So using pip, I went to install it. Unfortunately, pip pulled in PyQT5 as a prerequisite for QScintilla2. And that broke my "real" text editor, the one I have been using for over a decade and had all of my automation for this blog. It also cut me off from the rest of my "in progress" writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started troubleshooting, with an eye to restoring my machine to where it was before the offending package landed. I removed it, but when I went to install the proper version, the server with the files kept timing out on the downloads. The server assumed that my computer had given up and terminated the download after a couple of minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustration mounted, driving me to pack up the laptop, drive to the library and fix the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/4 of a gigabyte of downloading later, I had my editor (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.leoeditor.com/"&gt;Leo&lt;/a&gt;) back up and running. I also updated my system and downloaded fresh code for Leo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All is well. Maybe I will even get in some writing before daughter comes home from school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>frustration</category><category>internet</category><guid>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/ugh-speed-matters/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 21:19:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sippy Straw</title><link>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/sippy-straw/</link><dc:creator>Chris George</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our internet sucks. We live on a farmlet on the wrong side of the tracks. Xplornet is our provider, and in all fairness they do a decent job. The speed isn't bad, but it isn't quite good enough for video conferencing. And the bandwidth cap (100GB/month) precludes Youtube or Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a teenager and a preteen in the house, that bandwidth cap is regularly breached. We already pay $100 for the 100GB, the next option is a 150GB plan for an additional $50 per month. We are considering it, but with spring coming on we will likely get by as people start spending more time outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part that really sucks is using the 100GB and still having six days of month left. They restrict our account once we hit the 100GB mark. We pay for 5MB/sec download speed; they cut it down to 200K/sec. It is interesting how much of the Internet becomes unusable at that speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got all excited last week when they sent out a flyer offering 200GB/mo at 25MB/sec speeds for $99.00 for the first year and $149.00 after that. Turns out that we got it in our mailbox by "mistake". Part of our postal code is a bit north of our place, some more of it to the west. The promotion applies to a new satellite that is currently serving the north of the province. There is some thin hope that a similar promotion will roll here in the next couple of months...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, another five days of what we call "sippy straw" internet. I guess it beats dial-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>fwp</category><category>internet</category><guid>https://www.chrisgeorge.ca/posts/sippy-straw/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 15:11:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>